Tony Edvalson

linkedin.com/in/tonyedvalson tonyedvalson@gmail.com 603.801.4358

Software engineer with 7 years of experience in ML/AI, technical leadership, and full stack development. Proven success in optimizing large-scale systems at Google Play, significantly improving performance for 2.5 billion users. Skilled in leading technical teams and driving project innovations. Aiming to solve complex technical challenges and enhance product capabilities with AI/ML techniques.

Work Experience

Google Play // Software Engineer III

Dec 2021 - Present

Managed multiple petabyte-scale data pipelines and backend services for Android's flagship app store.

- Developed large-scale pipelines using user data and machine optimization techniques, reducing app install times by 30%.
- Took on the role of technical lead, oversaw issue triage, led multi-quarter development projects, and coordinated cross-team efforts to innovate and meet new international compliance requirements.
- Mentored 4 new team members and doubled the amount of documentation to improve onboarding and project maintenance.

IBM // Software Developer Intern

Jun 2021 — Aug 2021

Coordinated across departments to develop novel deep learning models and AI solutions. Enhanced long-term weather forecasting capabilities using Tensorflow and IBM cloud tools, employing PCA, convolutional neural networks, and extreme value theory. The new model tripled the accuracy of predicting extreme weather events 2 months in advance from 13% to 42%.

PickUp Patrol // Founder

Apr 2014 - Nov 2021

Created an industry-leading cloud-based web application and mobile app for K-12 schools. Led product inception, frontend and backend design, sales, and pitching to investors. The company consists of 7 full time employees and serves over 650 schools internationally.

- Implemented a distributed and highly scalable architecture that supports 550,000 users internationally.
- In response to the COVID-19 pandemic, I drove the development of 2 new products within 6 weeks to address new needs in the ed-tech market. These products brought a 270% increase in sales.

Projects

Apollo // Al Music Generation

2024

Apollo uses ML and signal processing techniques to generate music. It utilizes variational autoencoders, modified ResNet blocks, and specialized loss functions to generate music within a latent representation.

Bolt // Interactive LLMs for Web Development

2023

Bolt is a coding assistant that allows users to develop websites in plain English. It can edit, correct errors, and implement complex interactions from scratch, like modals, shopping carts, and checkout functionality.

Education

Rochester Institute of Technology - BS Computer Science

Skills

Languages - Java, Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, Go, CSS, HTML, C# .NET, CUDA **Frameworks -** React, TensorFlow, Angular, Docker, numpy, pandas, GCP, SQL